安徽省二零二三年初中学业水平考试。
,2023 secondary test
一短对话理解，你将听到五段对话。
每段对话后有一个小题，请在每小题所给的
A, B, C Please I'm taking a paper cutting class.
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项。
每段对话读两遍。
I've cut a tiger and a horse out of paper.
Sounds fun! If I have the chance, I'm going to cut out a
2. Did you go climbing and swimming last weekend as planned?
No, instead, I practiced rowing a for the coming Dragon Boat Festival.
Did you go climbing and swimming last weekend as planned?
3. What time does the film start?
At five o Oh, hurry up!
It's already a quarter to five now.
What time does the film start?
At five o Oh, hurry up!
It's already a quarter to five
4. How do you feel about the coming new term,
Well, I'm really looking forward to it.
I can't wait to see my friends again.
How do you feel about the coming new term, Lucy?
Well, I'm really looking forward to it.
I can't wait to see my friends again.
5. Excuse me, how can I find the book, The Old Man and the Sea?
Sorry, I'm afraid it has been sold out.
5. I'm afraid out.
听下面一段对话，回答第六、七题。
I'm afraid Sorry, been Sorry, afraid Sorry,
I'm Sorry, I'm afraid Sorry, afraid Sorry, I'm out.
I'm out. Sorry, I'm afraid
Yes, very funny.
But seriously, what are you doing?
I'm reading in the study.
Why? I'm in Renmin Park, selling homemade cakes with my classmates.
We want to raise money for wild animals.
Wow, it's meaningful.
How about coming to join us?
Okay, I'll be there soon.
听下面一段对话，回答第八至十题。
you. Excuse me, I'm a reporter from our school newspaper.
I'm doing a survey.
Could I ask you a couple of questions?
Sure. Thank you.
Earth Day is coming.
What are you going to do for it?
I'm going to join in an activity held by the library.
Oh, great. Can you tell me more about it?
Okay, it's an art competition.
Anyone can enter.
You have to make art with used things.
How interesting. What are you going to make?
I am going to make a tree with used milk boxes and my father's old ties.
I want to call on people to plant more trees.
Cool. You're saving our Earth.
Good luck in the competition.
Thank you. Excuse me, I'm a reporter from our school newspaper.
I'm doing a survey.
Could I ask you a couple of questions?
Sure. Thank you.
Earth Day is coming.
What are you going to do for it?
I'm going to join in an activity held by the library.
Oh, great. Can you tell me more about it?
Okay, it's an art competition.
Anyone can enter.
You have to art with used things.
How interesting. What are you going to make?
I am going to make a tree with used milk boxes and my father's old ties.
I want to call on people to plant more trees.
Cool. You're saving our Earth.
Good luck in the competition.
Thank you. Thank you.
三，短文理解。
也，你将听到一篇短文，短文后有五个小题，请根据短文内容，在每小题
所给的
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项。
短文读两遍。
Hello, everyone. I'm a student from Singapore.
My hobby is traditional Chinese music.
When I was seven, I began to have Arhu lessons.
Then I formed a music group with my friends.
And we've been in the group for four years.
Every year we play at our school art festival.
We even won the school talent show two years ago.
And we've already written ten songs of our own.
Half of them were written by me.
My biggest dream is to hold my own concert in Hong Kong.
To achieve it, I've decided to learn music in China.
So my parents will send me to Shanghai next year.
I'll be there for two years.
I plan to find a part -time job while studying there.
I hope my dream will come true one day.
Hello, everyone. I'm a student from Singapore.
My hobby is traditional Chinese music.
When I was seven, I began to have Arhu lessons.
Then I formed a music group with my friends.
And we've been in the group for four years.
Every year we play at our school art festival.
We even won the school talent show two years ago.
And we've already written ten songs of our own.
Half of them were written by me.
My biggest dream is to hold my own concert in Hong Kong.
To achieve it, I've decided to learn music in China.
So my parents will send me to Shanghai next year.
I'll be there for two years.
I plan to find a part -time job while studying there.
I hope my dream will come true one day.
四信息转换。
你将听到一篇短文，请根据短文内容写出下面表格中所缺的单词，每空仅
填一词。
短文读两遍。
Thank you watching.
What does kindness mean to you?
some people, it's smiling to cheer someone up.
And for others, it means saying something nice or helping someone with a task.
Kindness can be learned.
And it's something we can get better at with practice.
Here are some ways to be kind.
First of all, we can read about kind people so that we can learn from them.
A smile is also a simple way to show kindness.
It can make others happy.
Smile spreads the message of kindness from person to person.
praise someone is another way that we can show our kindness.
Perhaps you could tell a how smart or pretty they are.
All in all, to be kind is very important to everyone.
What does kindness mean to you?
some people, it's smiling to cheer someone up.
And for others, it means saying something nice or helping someone with a task.
Kindness can be learned.
And it's something we can get better at with practice.
Here are some ways to be kind.
First of all, we can read about kind people so that we can learn from them.
A smile is also a simple way to show kindness.
It can make others happy.
spreads the message of kindness from person to person.
To praise someone is another way that we can show our kindness.
Perhaps you could tell a friend how smart or pretty they are.
All in all, to be kind is very important to everyone.